[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
In this module, we will discuss some very important fundamental concept,
وسنناقش في هذا الوحدة بعض المفاهيم الأساسية الهامة،
which is evaluating classifiers.
والتي تقيم المصنفون.
And in particular, we talked about precision-recall, which is a concept
وتحدثنا على وجه الخصوص عن مفهومي الدقة والإرجاع
that's widely used, way beyond some of the classifiers we talked about here.
واللذانِ يُستخدمان على مجال واسع بشكل يتجاوز بعض المصنِفون الذين تناولناهم بالحدث هنا،
So basically any classification problem you're going to see in industry.
إلى أي مشكلة تصنيف يمكن أن تواجها في هذه الصناعة.
We saw that just straight accuracy or
فلقد استنتجنا أن المقاييس الرئيسية
error metrics may not be the right things for your application.
الواضحة للدقة أو الخطأ قد لا تكون الأنسب لتطبيقك.
And you need to look at something else and
وأنت بحاجة للتقصي عن شيء آخر،
precision recall is one of the first things you might want to look at.
ويعتبر مفهوم الدقة والإرجاع أحد الأمور التي يجب البحث فيها.
Precision captures the fraction
تلتقط الدقة جزء التوقعات الإيجابية الخاص بك
of your top of your positive predictions that are actually positive and
والتي تكون إيجابية بالفعل،
recall talks about of all positive predictions positive sentences out there,
وتناول الإرجاع التنبؤات الإيجابية للجمل الإيجابية الموجودة هناك.
which ones did you find, which ones did you label as positive.
أيٍ منهم قد وجدتها، وأيٍ منهم أسميتها بالإيجابية.
So we talked about the trade-off in between precision and recall,
لذا فقد تحدثنا عن المقايضات بين الدقة والإرجاع،
and how you can navigate that trade-off with that trade-off parameter t,
وكيفية تحريك المقايضة مع معلم المقايضة t،
in terms of probability, and really get this beautiful precision trade-off curves.
من حيث الاحتمالية، والحصول على تلك المقايضة الرائعة والدقيقة للمنحنيات.
And finally, we talked about comparing models with this precision at k metric,
وتحدثنا أخيرًا عن مقارنة النماذج من خلال هذه الدقة في مقياس K.
which is one that I particularly like for a lot of applications.
والذي أفضله شخصيًا للكثير من التطبيقات.
I want to take a moment here to thank my colleague, Krishna Sridhar,
وأود أن أشكر في هذا المقام زميلي كريشنا سريدهار،
who is instrumental at helping these slides come together and
والذي يعتبر صاحب دور فعال في المساعدة على جمع هذه الشرائح معًا
creating the ideas behind this module
وخلق الأفكار لهذا النموذج.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]